hey dudes uh
name's ritman
matt ritman
and today i'm going to show you how to
create a laser beam and
take that laser beam and etch a logo
into a piece of metal so you can etch
anything your logo some text
anything anything you want so
this is what i did in mine
and i apologize for the slow
frame rate here i'm not on the fastest
machine in the world
so we've got some sparks a little bit of
smoke
that was done in after effects
so
we'll go ahead and create the etching
effect first in cinema 4d and we'll take
that into
into after effects and create the smoke
and the sparks
so with that
um the first thing we need to do is pull
up our logo
and mine is in adobe
illustrator um or some people call it is
illustrator but
you know i don't really know the what
the
real name is anyway
um so we've got our logo here and uh i
work for a company called dz so
so i etched
just the white part of the logo
in in the piece of metal
and one thing you kind of want to make
sure of
when you got your logo here is that it's
clean you know all your points you got a
minimum amount of points just enough to
get your logo you don't want any
straight points
and you got your a closed path
so
so you got your logo
first thing you need to do
so
in my case i'm going to copy the the
words dz to my clipboard
and then i'm going to fire up
photoshop
so we'll just
come over here
and just create a new
file new document
and it's already got the width and the
height
in
because we copied it to the clipboard so
hit ok
and
go ahead and paste in
your logo and we want to paste it as a
path
okay so hit ok
and there you can see it
i'm going to go ahead and hide in the
background
well
it doesn't really matter um anyway
now what we want to do is export this
path to illustrator it's kind of weird
going back and forth but this is what
you got to do so file
export
paths to illustrator
or illustrator excuse me
um work path okay
and we'll just save it to the desktop
logo.ai
here we go here it is
okay you can close out of
photoshop
i
won't be needing that anymore we can
close out illustrator too
just make my machine a little bit faster
i'm not on a fast computer folks okay
now um go ahead and uh
come over to cinema
all right so we got our cinema
now um go ahead and just open
up our logo
that we saved to the desktop
all right okay and we got the adobe
illustrator import dialog box
everything looks good here make sure
connect splines is disabled and group
splines
is checked okay
and you'll see that it is grouped under
a null called logo
okay
and here we have it
and uh
we've got five paths here
because they're all there's five
separate paths um path five is the deep
part of the d the inside of it
you can actually just drag this out
and down
yeah we can actually take all these
paths out of the null object we don't
need them grouped under a null and we
can delete the null so
and uh
just to kind of keep organized we're
going to rename these paths and put them
in the right order just uh
to keep it easy so
we're just going to call this one one
we're going to call this one two
and
we're going to call the e
three
and this is uh the order that it's going
to write onto the screen that's why i'm
doing this so
four
and five okay
and then we're gonna reorder these so
that it
is in sequential order
okay so one two three four five
so you'll see that it just goes in order
okay
um
now
next part next thing we want to do is uh
as our laser comes down and etches in
each each letter here
we kind of have to tell it where it's
going to start the path
where it's going to start writing so in
my case i started um on the top left
corner of each each letter here
or each each spline so
um
so for the d e
um if we go over here to our point tool
you'll notice that it actually starts
right here and that's not what we want
we want it to start up here in this
corner so highlight the point
and right click and select set first
point
and you'll notice it starts from white
and kind of fades into a dark blue
this is the direction i want to go so
the white is the start of the path and
the blue is the end of the path
so that one's good to go number two
um this one also needs to be
um set a new first point so set that
okay here we have a problem um
you'll see that it's reversed
so it's really easy
we want to
right click and select reverse sequence
and then i don't know why it does this
but it makes the new first point so it
puts it down here
so just
select it and hit set first point and
now it's in the right direction
okay so
number three
um same thing
you'll notice it's going in the wrong
direction so first thing we're gonna do
is
reverse sequence then i'm gonna hit set
first point
that's correct okay number four
yep same thing reverse sequence
set first point
okay so that one's good to go five
reverse sequence
and set first point
okay
because this is where the laser is going
to start just a reminder so laser starts
here and goes around
okay um next thing i want to do is just
uh
i'm just going to
rotate
my logo here
90 degrees
just so it's
flat
or negative 90 degrees here
so our laser will come from the top and
hit uh hit our logo
okay
so now we need to make this logo
actually 3d so first thing we do is grab
a sweep nerve
and then we grab
an inside
and i like inside because you have more
control over
the amount of polygons so i'm going to
use that
okay group that under the sweep nurb
and then take your number one
well first uh yeah let's uh
grab the inside and uh
let's see here
we're gonna change the radius to
six and our number of sides to eight
okay
and then we're just gonna
take we're just gonna take our one and
group it under the the sweep nurb
and inside has to be first
okay so
there we go look at that the d e
is now 3d
3d d e say that 10 000 times fast
okay
so we go
over number two we want to make that 3d
as well so
um
yep same thing uh
go ahead and just create a sweeper
sweep nerves uh
move it down
uh grab an inside
six radius
eight sides
um
oops
put the inside as a child of the sweep
um to make this quicker we're going to
just
copy this down a few times
okay
now this would be a lot quicker
okay there's that one put three in
um
put
four
into this one and we'll put five
and two this one sorry for all the
confusion
okay
and then i'm going to rename these again
to uh their numbers just so it's easier
to keep track
so
okay four
five okay
okay
so we've got our uh
each part of the logo in order here
uh huh okay
um okay so to animate
these um
pieces of logo coming onto the screen
um
in our sweet nerve each one of our
sweetener we have what's called an end
growth
you'll notice if you start pulling this
back it
moves the path
it kind of
builds it on to the screen so as you
increase the the end growth amount so
that's what we're going to be animating
here
so
um
with that let's uh
start uh and we want to get our key
frames all set up so
we're gonna set our key amount of
keyframes over here to
let's just go 500
okay drag this over
good
okay so
so the de
i go ahead and create a keyframe for the
end growth at frame 0
by holding down
command
and pressing this
circle
and you'll see it's red to indicate that
we've set a keyframe at frame 0. okay
so we move her over
we're gonna move it over to frame 89
89 okay
set a new keyframe and you'll notice our
first problem move the slider back to
zero
we forgot to change this to 100 or to
zero percent so change that to zero
and create a new keyframe
there so now it builds on
onto the screen okay good
okay so
for each letter
um
or each each uh spline path one two
three four five
i'm going to do it one keyframe before
the the whole number 90 so
um
so at frame 90
the 2 is going to start animating on so
change the end growth to zero
okay
keyframe
and for this one we're just going to go
to 139
okay keyframe it yep good okay number
three
same thing 140
um
and growth zero
keyframe it on and we're gonna
put this one at 2
19.
okay 100 percent
keep frame it
okay 220
number four
zip
keyframe
um this is a bigger section so we're
going to add a little more
keyframage
to three nineteen okay
so one hundred percent
key frame
theory of money
sorry for the repetitiveness here
um
okay zero
keyframe
and
now we'll just go to 400
or i'm sorry 3.99
100 percent
okay keyframe
so there we have it it writes on from
zero to frame 400.
and since we're only doing 400 frames
we'll just change the maximum keyframes
to 400.
okay so
you'll notice it's going to write on
one problem here is that when it starts
writing each letter it starts off really
slow speeds up and then slows down again
so watch it'll kind of speed up
and slow down
that is because our keyframes are set to
um i'm having a brain fart here let me
just switch it over
switch your layout over to animation
okay
and you'll notice over here
we have one two three four five
everything that's been animated in our
scene
but we need to switch our key mode to f
curves
okay and just select all your objects
okay so
so we have these curves um it's curving
because
it starts slow speeds up and slows down
again
but we want these to be linear
interpolation so
just select all your
you can either hit command a to copy or
to select everything and then
or you can do it by dragging and
selecting the
all your keyframes and then up here just
change it to
linear interpolation and then they'll be
straight okay
so we can switch back over to our
standard layout
and then if we hit play
it animates on at the same
the same rate throughout the entire
letter or throughout the entire
spline so
all right
okay
so
now when we etch this laser on
uh
in my animation anyway if you look
closely you'll see that
the material that i used it's kind of it
starts off orange and then kind of fades
back down to a gray color
just cut to kind of signify that it's
cooling off
as it etches into the metal
so
to do that let's go ahead and just
create a new material
double clicking down here
okay let's open up our material editor
all right so
i'm not going to use color
um
for
the luminance
we're going to add a luminance and we
are going to add
a gradient
okay
and then if we open up our gradient
settings
we're going to create our color so
color is going to start off kind of a
dark gray
and you don't have to have this perfect
just kind of get in the general
area here and then it's going to go to a
yellow
and you're going to you just click
here to create another color swatch
so we're going to do like a
yellow here
a little bit darker
okay yellow i'm going to create another
one
this one's going to be an orange
i'm going to create another one
and this one's going to be red
deeper red
and our last color is going to be back
to our dark
gray here
okay
and for the type
um this needs to be
2d v
2d dash v
okay
all right
then we're going to add
a little bit of reflection
and to that reflection we're gonna add a
fresnel
don't ask just do it
i don't know why
okay
um we got our specular okay we're gonna
add a little bit of glow
okay
inner strength we're going to set that
to 15
outer strength
radius
5 centimeters
it's not much but it's just enough
okay
and for our luminance channel
we might need to expand these
a little further here
okay
it should work out
okay so
we just need to apply our material to
each one of our sweet nurbs
okay
and we'll just drag these down here
all right
so there we have it
okay
now
to animate the glowing
effect
um we are going to
set
okay if you click on the texture tag
we're going to animate the offset v
you'll notice that
as you
move the offset v
it kind of moves around
and that's what we wanted to do
um i'm sorry i need to adjust the
gradient it's just not right
so pull up our gradient
yeah that's our problem this one right
here should not be should not be white
it should be dark gray and there should
be way over here
or
yeah
just bear with me here
i'm pretty new at this
okay
that's what we want
it's a two dark grays
okay close it out
good okay
click on our texture tag
there that's what we want we want to
start off a yellow kind of a yellow
color we might even shorten the yellow
down
um
so it's not quite as long
okay
shorten all just shorten all this down
we don't want a big long streak of
colors here
okay
there that looks that looks about right
there
i'm going to change the offset to back
to zero
okay so
it's gonna start off
right here
yep write a zero okay
so um
one thing we need to make sure of is
that when you move this offset v
we want it to
stick to the uv so if we click on our
sweep nurb
make sure you select sticky v's
and we're gonna actually do that for all
these here so
stick uvs okay
just do it
so okay
all right so there we go
um let's go ahead and animate this
moving around here
so
offset v for this particular one
oh yes that's why i did the stick uv
sorry i'm not explaining myself but uh
you'll notice when you move this
the
timeline slider that the uh
this color the gradient texture stays at
the top
and if we didn't do that
so i just unselected it
it's no longer here
it'll just stay
it stays at the back and that's not what
we want so
make sure you select stay qvs
okay
all right so frame zero
um select our texture tag
create a keyframe
okay move it over
to frame
oh yeah for this
we actually want to
yeah i think 80 00 to 89 again um
and then
change your offset
create a keyframe
at 89 as well so
hold on just a minute here
i think this needs to be zero
yes
so frame zero offset zero okay frame 89
whoa
frame 89
what's going on here
yep so keep it at 100
got it done
let's see make sure
okay that looks good there
in my animation i had this texture um
keep moving around so
i'm not gonna do that right now it's
just going to take too long
so
bear with me
okay so but
one problem i was having i could not
figure out why
is that
the gradient starts off very small and
as you get to the last part
of the end growth it's really long
couldn't figure that out so
sorry i don't know
how to fix it
um anyway so
let's move on to our next letter here
so offset
keyframe it
okay so we're gonna go around
to 139
keyframe it
okay
for the
second
part of the e
start at 140
select our next check texture tag
change the offset to 100
keyframe
move it around
to 219
okay 100
okay good
all right
moving right along
offset 100
keyframe
sorry this is so repetitive but you're
just gonna have to live with it
okay
all right so
keyframe
hold on just a hair
i don't know why i'm setting keyframes
because it stays no matter what
okay
anyway
i'm just going to continue because
that's what i did my animation i don't
remember why so
um
okay so
keyframe that
go to our end
a new keyframe
so there we have it
seems as if i made an error
oh yeah i don't know why that's at zero
okay so keyframe
all right so there we have it um
we have not made our li our laser yet
but uh this is what we we start with um
our logo being animated onto the screen
so say we want a piece of metal in here
just grab a
cube
okay we're just going to center that
with our logo here
just kind of give it a general idea
um
we're going to just change the size x to
change that to
yeah it looks good there
and the thickness we're going to make it
a thin piece
and
our z
just kind of
just do 850
and just to make these even 50.
and 21 30. okay
so there we have our piece of metal here
and my animation it looks like it's
engraving but it's really not
um
mine just uh
had it sitting
just above the the piece of metal
and you could actually go in here and
intersect it with a boolean but mine was
wasn't working correctly so
i'm not actually going to intersect
anything
because it's so far away it doesn't
really matter you can't see that it's
really engraving it anyway so
this is what we're gonna do
so
i've got a piece of metal i'm gonna give
it just a
quick texture of uh
you know what
why it's fine
so we can see a little better
okay
so
to create our laser
um
the laser needs to point at
a null object
so to do that um
we're going to create we're going to
animate a null object moving from spline
to spline
so it's going to animate five different
locations so
create a null object okay
all right so we have our null
now
go ahead and right click and we're going
to give this null object
and align to spline tag
and then for the spline path
we're going to choose our first spline
path
i'm just gonna
um pull all these down so it's easier
but uh so at frame zero
frame zero we want spline path to be
one
okay
and set a keyframe for the spline path
at 1.
so
it's going to animate around
then at frame
90.
we want spline path to be 2 so drag 2 in
a 90
and set a keyframe
okay
then animate this around
then at 140
number three
set a keyframe
then at 220
for
sorry for the repetitiveness
and the uh
well just how boring my voice is okay i
apologize
i'm not the best tutor
i'm gonna admit it
okay
five
done
so as these animate onto the screen our
null object
switches
to each spline
see how it moves
okay
so
um
let's see here
now we want the null object to follow
um
our path around
we have it switching to each path but
now we want to actually follow the path
as it
animates on so
to do that
you just animate the position here
so frame zero position zero
okay frame 89
position
okay and then here is a problem
see
how the uh
no object kind of lags behind and then
goes past
and then
ends
first
it's not lining up so the reason for
that is
remember earlier when we set the
interpolation to linear
well we need to do that again
but first let's just go ahead and
animate all these on so we can do
do all that at once so
um
okay so frame 90
set position
to zero
key frame
okay so 140
position zero
okay 220
zero
set a keyframe
or three 319 i'm sorry
320 we want it to be zero percent
and 400
and then keyframe
so
it kind of lags behind each one here
so to fix that
um change our layout over to animation
and select align to spline
and select all of our keyframes
and make sure you put it on
linear
okay
change back over to
standard
and we're still gonna have an issue
you'll find
so if i hit play
it's still gonna
lag behind and speed up
okay the reason for that is
if you click on
our number one spline you have to do
this to each one
the intermediate points is set to
adaptive
that actually needs to be set to uniform
so
select the remaining uh your remaining
splines
and change the intermediate points to
uniform
and that should
fix our problem of the null
not
staying up with our path okay so now it
stays at the very end of our path
and it's at the beginning
okay
so
you know what happens from there
okay
so the next thing we want to do now is
create our laser beam
so
a laser beam
is
a
light so create a light
all right and just move it up here
okay
the light needs to be the type of light
is a parallel
spot
okay parallel spot
okay
we don't want a shadow visible light we
need to change that to visible
when it renders we want to see it
okay
and we don't want to illuminate a scene
so no illumination
okay
now
rotate it 90 degrees
negative 90 degrees
okay
there we have it our laser beam looks
fantastic okay
now
we need to change a few other
properties in our light
we don't want to diffuse
so just deselect it
okay
so
now go over to our details tab
and we're going to change the inner
radius
we're going to change that to three
outer radius six
and
if we go over to our visibility tab
we need to change the falloff to zero
and
edge falloff change that to 70.
um
inner distance change that to 25
centimeters
and
let's see here
you'll notice
our outer distance is at 500 that's just
how long the the beam
oops
so the outer distance is how long the
beam
how long it is so
there we have that
so to kind of get a color for a laser
beam
right now if we render it i'm just going
to do a region render
it's not too bad
it's just white so say we want kind of a
gradient
like a blue laser bluish laser
if we go over
down under visibility select use
gradient
okay and we're going to start from white
and we're going to go
to kind of a light blue
that looks good there
and we want a little more blue so i'm
going to drag the blue end down in here
okay so now if we render it
okay
you know i'm gonna give our scene just a
little bit of light so it's easier to
see
just create a little omni light
from the distance there
okay
and i'm gonna turn on
shadows
all right
so our laser beam let's just go ahead
and name that laser so it's easy to
understand
okay
whoa
all right
okay i messed up the view so we need to
frame default
i don't know why cinema does that but
sometimes
when you move around it rotates funny so
okay i'm gonna move the laser kind of up
and kind of out of the screen a little
bit
and then we're gonna take our uh
at our distance and pull that down
so if we render it now
we got kind of a nice little
beam coming down here
all right so
we want to animate this laser
following our our null object so
to do that
we we're going to add a target
expression to our laser
so right click
cinema 4d
target
alright
and what do we want to target we want to
target our null object
so just drag that
in
okay
and
i'm going to rename the null object to
just laser tip
so now if we hit play
you'll see that
it follows it around
but we have another problem
uh see our
end we want the end to actually match
the distance
um
to where it is and you'll
obviously in the center it's going to be
a shorter distance but out here
when when our laser is pointing all the
way to our last e
we have a longer distance here
so we want that distance to change
depending on
where it is so
to do that um let's see here
okay
um we need to add a little bit of
espresso
so
we're gonna add some an espresso tag to
our laser
so right click cinema 4d tags expresso
all right here we go expresso editor
i'm going to name this light to just
scene light
okay
so
to do this
just drag in your
laser okay there we have it
all right
then on the blue
we got this little blue input here we
need to go
if you just click on it it pulls up this
menu
if you go down to visibility
we want to change the vl outer distance
that was that same value that
that i was changing earlier to to change
the how far the beam goes so
that's what we want
so
to make this work
i'm going to drag in another laser
okay
and on the red
i'm going to pull that down
i'm going to go to coordinates
global position global position
okay and then
i want to
drag in my laser tip
so
laser tip
okay on the red
again same thing
you want a global position so click it
coordinates global position global
position
all right
um and then
let's see here
move these here
we want a new
note so if you just right click in here
go to new node
um espresso
calculate
we want to calculate the distance
so
the position of the laser and the laser
tip calculating the distance and we're
gonna
output that to our outer distance so all
you have to do is connect these up
global position on our laser tip input
one
our laser global position input two and
output of our distance node
to the input of the laser
at a distance
and that's it
you can actually go ahead and just close
that out and
now you'll notice
if we just hit play
it always stays at the very tip
of our
edge of our etching animation so
stays at the tip um
all right
so
now next
okay
okay so in my animation also you noticed
that there was a
kind of a bright
tip
actual light lighted tip on the end of
this and i kind of flickered just to
kind of give it a little bit of effect
um so to do that
just add in a new light
okay
and
we need to make this a child
of our
laser tip
because
it's going to follow that around
actually uh before we do that
i'm sorry
um just change our
key
keyframe to zero
we want to put this light position it
right with our laser tip here
okay
so we're just gonna move it down
and
down and i'm going to turn on snapping
so if we tear this off
enable snapping 3d
we want point snapping
and if i just move this over it should
snap to our tip
or not
wait
let's just do axis snapping
there axis snapping my bad
okay you can close that
out and turn off snapping
all right so
right now it's just going to be a bright
light so we need to change
how our laser looks okay
so
oh first uh
make this light
the light tip a late or a child of laser
tip no object okay
and we want to be kind of an orange
so just change it to an orange color
all right
um okay so we want this the visible
light we want that to be visible
um i don't want to illuminate
and
um details
i think
um actually okay visibility
we want to change the outer distance
just make it real small
and let's see how that looks
okay
just make it a little bigger
okay so we got kind of a
end beam kind of a bright light here
that's cool
okay so
as this moves around we want to kind of
flicker a little bit so
to do that we're going to do some more
espresso so over here on our light
laser tip light right click cinema 4d
tags espresso
okay
to do this just drag in your light
okay um
and on the blue input
we need to change
the or we need to add
general
intensity that's what we're going to be
affecting here so over in our light if
over here
under the general
the intensity is the brightness
so we're going to be affecting the
brightness
so
all we have to do to make this flicker
is create a new node espresso
um let's see
general
noise
just give a little bit of noise
okay and hook that up
and if you just if you click on here on
each one of these it changes the
attributes of each one so if you click
on noise we want our noise type to be
fractal brown movement
we want it to be positive only
i only want it to be brighter
okay
see octaves change that to 10.
change the scale to two
change frequency to five
and change the amplitude to three
don't ask i got these memorized i
actually have it written down so i'm
cheating a little bit i'm sorry okay
those are the values we want to use
so
if we hit play you can kind of
not see it but uh
as it moves around
see this here this
inner cir this inner crosshair it kind
of changes from
an orange to a yellow now
and
now it's
orange yep so it just kind of varies
so if we render this right here
it's sort of bright
but now if we
render it now
it should be even brighter
a little bit brighter you can see when
you actually animate it so
all right
moving on
okay
now
so we have our scene set up here
we pretty much got it so it laser etches
on and when you set up your
your view make sure that the top the
laser is not showing it's just kind of
coming
from the top of the screen
so
there we have it
all right
okay
so
basically we're going to export
this into after effects
and to do that you need to make sure
that you install
the
the cinema 4d plugin into the after
effects
adobe after effects library
so
just to show you quick if we minimize
this
if we navigate to our cinema 4d
directory
applications
um
let's see
max on
cinema 4d
um exchange plugins
after effects
exporter
os x
i have cs 5.5 so
um you'll notice that we have a zip file
if you
unzip it
it gives us our our plug-in actual
plug-in so all you have to do is drag
this plug-in into the
directory of our after effects
so
i also noticed
there was an importer plugin
the same thing
um go ahead and do that with with this
one as well
so
unzip it and just grab both those
plugins and copy them over into our
after effects
plugin folder which is
on a mac if you have a mac
macs are way better by the way if you
don't have a mac
get one
just uh
they're better okay
anyway
you can argue with me all day but uh
i'll win that's just the way it is so
um okay so if we go under after effects
folder
we have a plugin directory plugins
that's where you copy those
you can see i already have done that so
right there
you have to do this okay
so
um if we come back into cinema
and
oh one thing i forgot on this light
um
we need to have it illuminate so uncheck
no illumination
because if we do that if we don't have
illumination
then
after effects won't know to use that as
a emitter type so
we need to
leave that unchecked
okay and then we're going to name that
laser
tip oh yeah okay and then i remembered
on
see when we animate this all out
um just go to the last frame here
it leaves behind our texture
and if we render this you can see the
gradients
um
well
let's see
oh yes um
okay so it cycle was selected
and when you hit render you can see that
it's
you can see the gradients
what we needed to do was unselect cycle
and the luminance
so if you get a luminance and then
gradient
if you unselect cycle
so then
um okay so when it animates this d on
you see it
and
when it gets to here
okay you still see it
let me make sure
okay we need to animate the
end
um let's see so if we go to the texture
tag
and you click
okay so it's
from 89
to
let's just go
to 98
this offset needs to
go to
so it's gonna anything past this point
so it's down here it'll be hidden so
we'll just go to twenty percent
set a keyframe
so this next one
the number two texture
um so 139 it's already got a keyframe
we'll just do
okay 139
should be at zero
and
we'll just do 150
we'll do 20 percent
okay same for this one here
number three
should be at zero when it starts
and
when it ends
should be at 20
right let me see let's start at zero
leave it at zero
right here should be at 20
we just want to go past a little bit so
okay that one's it
okay
i apologize for this
oh
okay
didn't have the right one selected
okay just bear with me while i fix this
zero
to
20 percent
so when number five starts
we hit zero
and it goes around
yeah actually this one will be a little
further
well that's not going to work
i'll just be a zero
okay the last ones uh we'll just have to
change the number of keyframes to
and then
move this over
there
okay so now that it's all rendered on
oops
all right
we need to undo my view change here
view
a new view okay
so now if we render this
you won't see any of the gradients
and also i want to change just my scene
light so we don't have these shadows
down here so i'm just going to take my
scene light
and switch to a different viewport
top
i'm just going to kind of move it over
the top
okay so now when it renders we won't
have
two craziest shadows it's still got some
but yeah i'm gonna adjust it a little
bit more
okay
and i'm gonna move my floor up
i'm not
it's all right where it is
all right
i don't like the shadows it just looks
like it's
okay then i'm just gonna move my scene
light back to where it was
okay
all right
okay so that's what we got
all right um
so
okay and
we want to animate this over into
after effects
bring it over into after effects
so what we need to do is
create a compositing file so
let's go ahead and set up this
our set our render settings here
output we're going to change to
a film video preset we're just going to
do
hd tvd
hd
hd tv
720p 29.97
um and then we're going to change frame
range
all frames 0 to 420
save we want it to be a tiff sequence
which is correct
um
let's pull up our
dialogue here
um we're just going to save it as laser
we'll go ahead and create a new folder
on the desktop just name it laser
create
and laser so
um
basically we're gonna have 420 different
images
um
named laser laser one laser o2
we want alpha channel
so that when it renders it you won't see
the background here
it whatever's black it'll be
taken out so
okay so under compositing project file
we want to save that
and as after effects we've got we got
some other options here but we don't
want to use any of those so
obviously we're using after effects so
um
and we also want to include the 3d data
okay
so um close that out
and
select our scene camera
okay so now if we render this out
um
it'll render out our full sequence with
a compositing project file that we can
then open in after effects
so
i'm going to go ahead and start this
render and
i'll be back in just a minute
all right so
we are all done
rendering out all of our frames
so um let's go ahead and take our data
over into after effects and create our
sparks and our smoke
so we can close out of this
and
minimize cinema
we're going to pull up after effects
okay and uh
to create our smoke and our sparks
effects
i'm using a
plug-in for after effects called trap
code particular
it's from red giant
and it's just it does a phenomenal job
creating uh
particle emitters um
it's just it's so much better than uh
than cinema 4ds particle system so
i would highly recommend trap code
particular for after effects
so
to get started
just go to
after effects go to open
open
project
and we're gonna open
actually i'm sorry just double click in
the project window
and uh
to import a file and we're gonna import
our laser dot aec
it's for it's the after effects
composition file so go to open
okay spin this down
just double click the laser comp
and here we have it
it imported our camera
the scene light
the laser tip
and each frame is already animated
and then we have all of our frames or to
sequence right there so
here it is
we don't need the scene light
so we can go ahead and get rid of that
we do need the laser tip
okay and the way particular works is
any light
in your scene
you have to change the name to emitter
so we're going to change the laser tip
to emitter
and it uses that to track
where the emitter is so
wherever this light is which we imported
from cinema that's where the it's going
to emit particles so that's why it makes
it so much easier to
create a comp file
and do it in here and here so
so to create our sparks
let's go up to uh layer new solid
and we're just gonna name it sparks
okay make comp size it already is
all right
and we're going to apply the
particular effect so go to effect
trap code
particular
all right so
um
if we go into the emitter settings
the emitter type needs to be
lights
and that
right there will make it follow
our light see you'll notice
it already
if we play this back it
it's emitting particles from our light
that we imported from cinema
so that's pretty awesome
so to create our sparks
i've got some settings
and i'll just go down the list here
particles per second
is going to be 200
um
let's see
we want the direction to be
bidirectional
velocity we're going to change that to
200.
velocity random we're going to change
that to 54
velocity distribution to one
emitter size
for x y and z we're going to change that
to 10
for all three of these
okay and then we can minimize emitter
particle
life is going to be 1.5 seconds
um life random we're going to change
that to 22.
particle type is going to be a glow
sphere
and
our feather we're going to change that
to 46
we're going to change the size to 2
and this size over life
we can create
a curve
and we want it to do
something look
something like this
so and then you can hit the smooth
button it'll make it smooth
for you so
that's what you want to look like right
there
you want to start big and then go
small
right before its death so
okay so
um opacity over life
let's see
opacity over life the color
we're going to change that to
ff8656
kind of a peach color
and
we want the transfer mode to be add
and then if we spin down the glow
settings because
it's been turned on because we turned on
glow sphere up here
we want size to be zero
and opacity
to be eight
okay
so now if we
um we can minimize particle settings
if we go into the physics
settings
um
we want the mode
or the physics model to be bounce
and
gravity to 600
and if you take down the bounce settings
um
this is a problem um since we didn't
actually export
from cinema of the floor the piece of
metal
this is going to be a little more
difficult for the sparks to kind of have
some bounce but uh
let's see what we can do here um
because for the floor layer we could
create another solid here and use that
as a floor layer which and the sparks
would bounce off of it but
we're not going to be able to do that so
let's see if this will work change the
floor mode to layer size
collision event
to kill
and let's see
we gotta
spin down the auxiliary system which is
the sparks after it's hit
an object and then
the sparks that it creates from hitting
something
we want the emit to be at bounce event
and then i'll turn the bounce here on
and we want the bounce up here to be
the slide we want that to be 40.
okay and we're done with
the physics settings so
under auxiliary
um
we want
the probability
to be 20.
we want
velocity to be velocity to be 168.
size we want to be 1.5
okay the size over life
we just want a linear
curve down so
that's what we want to look like size
over life
and then opacity over life
yeah we want to just be a solid just
like this so that one's good
color over life
we want this to be actually just a solid
red so just delete these swatches
just like that so
okay and i don't know what just happened
but uh
okay
okay color from main
we want this to be
gravity we want that to be 600 again
and transfer mode we want add
control from main particles
um
inherent velocity
we want this to be
okay and
under the visibility settings
let's see here
obscure
the obscuration layer needs to be the
floor but we don't have a floor
um
or i'm sorry also obscure with
oh never mind
we just need to change also obscure with
just change that to floor
i'm not sure if this is going to work
but
let's just go ahead and try to add a
floor in i don't think it's going to
work very well but
if we go to layer new
solid
and just name it floor
and then we need to make it a 3d layer
so
if we click on this little
end and box here
we just need to orientate it
we're wearing it the right way so
we
rotate the x
i'm just going to kind of match the
the other floor we
are using here
um let's see
scale we're just going to scale it up
and scale it this way
and we need to change our view to
or the active camera
to custom view one
we can kind of
and then change the views to
four views
um
yeah this isn't gonna work very well
well let's see what we've got here
we're just going to move the floor down
below the emitter
so
and then hide the floor
change this view back to one view active
camera
and then if we
play this back
um
we can kind of see some sparks here but
we also need to change some more
settings so
click on your sparks and go to the
effects
tab and under rendering
um
we need to turn on
some motion blur
so
spin that down
and change this to
on
motion blur on
okay
the shutter angle change that to 720
the type needs to be
subframe sample
and levels we're going to change that to
17.
and opacity boost change that to 25.
so there we got
some better looking sparks here
um with our floor it's really hard to
judge
because we didn't
import that in so
i can't
quite say how
the depth where it needs to be
but uh
yeah um let's see here
actually
if we go back to our physics for the
sparks
the floor layer change that to floor
okay here we go
now our floor turn that back on
if we pull this down a bit
you can kind of see where they're
colliding
okay i hide that um
yeah that's a lot of sparks
anyway but you get the idea um okay for
smoke
we're just gonna move on
for smoke create a new solid in
and name it
smoke
all right
and do the same thing effect trap code
particular
okay
the emitter
make sure that is set to light so that
it follows our light around
all right just like that
okay
all right for some settings um this
one's a little easier um
particles per second change that to
velocity 81
okay we're done there
particle
change the life to one
life random to 100.
we want the particle type to be a
cloudlet
and the size needs to be 19
size random we want that to be 63
size over
life we want kind of a
um i have a bell curve here
um they already have a preset one in
here it's this one here so it looks just
like this
so we want the size overlap to be
then uh
opacity we want the opacity to be 1.5
and we can just
we're done with particle
um shading
um shadowlit from maine
needs to be on
and we're done there physics
air we want the air resistance to be
three
so
there that kind of gives us
some sparks
um
so if i rendered a little bit a little
snippet of this
probably have way too many sparks but
you can turn the
amount down so
but it gives you an idea it gives you
something to start with anyway
but that's kind of the effect we're
going after right there um
tons of sparks tons of smoke
you got it
so
with that i think that's about all i
wanted to show you today
um
hope you learned something if you have
any questions
feel free to email me and i'll try to
answer it as soon as i can
alright guys well thanks a lot i
appreciate you taking the time to watch
this see you around bye